# **Uma Prasad Das** Software Engineer

umaprasaddas1999@gmail.com 📞 7978175924 🐶 https://uma-das-portfolio.netlify.app

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

A skilled and highly motivated Software Engineer. 2+ years of experience in developing and implementing interactive web applications, enhanced by constant research and professional development. I am targeting growth-oriented organization of repute, having the capability of delivering quality products from scratch to production.

#### **SKILLS**

**Base:** — HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Typescript, Java

Frameworks: — Angular, Bootstrap, ReactJS

Task Runners: — Gulp, Webpack **Design** — Micro UI, Microservices

Databases — MySQL

Testing — Jasmine, Karma, Jest

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

07/2023 - 11/2023 Panasa Technology

Software Developer

- Re-designed and developed frontend solutions.
- Worked closely with the product teams in analyzing and providing solutions.
- Migrated successfully entire application from Flutter to Angular.
- Performance and quality improvement.
- Team management and API design and integration.

#### CitiusTech Healthcare Pvt. Ltd.

11/2021 - 05/2023

Software Engineer

- Developed and delivered a dynamic and responsive user experience by crafting efficient, welldocumented, and maintainable software, adhering to industry best practices.
- Managed to a 10% increase in operational efficiency by analyzing and troubleshooting software defects and issues.
- Implemented comprehensive unit testing, achieving 85% test coverage and significantly enhancing application stability and reliability.
- Part of a cross-functional team and developed a metadata driven user interface.

**ProLeap Academy** 05/2021 - 08/2021

Software Developer Intern

#### **EDUCATION**

## **B.Tech in Electronics and Communication Engineering**

07/2017 - 07/2021

National Institute of Science and Technology

# **PROJECTS**

## Organizational -

**SEND2**: A Payment Gateway and Payroll Product

Technologies: HTML, Bootstrap, Typescript, Angular, DJango, Python, MySQL

**MYGEHEALTHCARE:** A Healthcare Web App

Technologies: HTML, SASS, Typescript, Angular, NodeJS, AWS

# Personal:

These are few highlights of my personal projects TextUtils: An Online Text Conversion Tool Technologies: Angular, HTML, CSS, Typescript.

Buy and Sell: A Ecommerce Website that helps users to buy and sellers to sell their products online.

Technologies: Angular, HTML, CSS, Typescript.